reachmail.net 2018-08-02

# Privacy Policy | Reachmail

ReachMail is an email service provider. Our customers are businesses and organizations that use the ReachMail tool to send email marketing messages. ReachMail only allows customers to upload email lists of their customers who have given permission to the customer to send them email. ReachMail only sends messages to email addresses at the direction of our customers. ReachMail does not share, trade or sell email addresses and only maintains email addresses at the direction of our customers. If a customer terminates their account ReachMail will delete all addresses.

ReachMail is committed to the highest standards of Privacy and maintains a strict Anti-Spam policy.

**If you have had trouble removing yourself from a list sent via ReachMail using the opt-out link provided in the email, please FORWARD the message directly to[rem@reachmail.com](mailto:rem@reachmail.com) and we will promptly remove you.** The email must be forwarded, otherwise we will not know from which mailing list it originated. If you no longer have this email, please provide as much detail as possible, so we can identify the source of the mailing.

We do not tolerate spam and refuse to work with clients who blatantly send messages to recipients who have not clearly expressed an interest in receiving emails from our clients. We take issues of email abuse very seriously. **If you feel that you have been subjected to spam sent using ReachMail's services, please email[abuse@reachmail.com](mailto:abuse@reachmail.com) and we will investigate the matter promptly, including the complete removal of your name from the client(s) lists in question.**

ReachMail complies with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy for all individuals within the European Union (EU). Any ReachMail customer, sending to, or on behalf of any individual with the EU is also bound by the GDPR as detailed in the ReachMail GDPR Data Processing Addendum.

ReachMail Inc. complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. ReachMail Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)

**In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, ReachMail Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.** The type of data ReachMail collects includes name, email address, ip location, company name and telephone number. The purpose is to identify and communicate with our customers. Information is self reported by the customer except with IP location.

**European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact ReachMail Inc. at:**

ReachMail Inc.   
Attn: John Murphy   
Privacy Manager   
300 W Adams St   
Suite 612   
Chicago, IL 60603

Telephone: 312-229-0110

ReachMail does not share customer information with third parties. Information is shared internally to provide customer support only.

EU individuals have the right to access; correct; or delete their personal data.

An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct his query to the Privacy Manager. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe

ReachMail Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

ReachMail is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC)

We may be required to disclose an individual's personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield, ReachMail is potentially liable.

## Client Data Policy

Your recipient lists are stored on a secure ReachMail server. We do not, under any circumstances, steal your lists, contact people on your lists, market to people on your lists, sell your lists, or share your lists with any other party, except as required by law or, regarding contacting, except in response to a complaint or other communication directly from an individual on one of your lists. Only carefully selected, authorized personnel have access to view Distribution Lists. We do not hold your lists hostage. We do not make it difficult for you to reclaim them. You may export (download) your lists from ReachMail at any time so long as we have a copy. We will use and disclose the information in your Distribution Lists only for one or more of the following purposes:

  1. To help enforce compliance with our Terms of Use and applicable law including, but not limited to, helping to create white lists and black lists, to develop and test algorithms, heuristics and other methods and tools for detecting violations, and to apply those methods and tools.
  2. **To bill and collect sums owed to us.**
  3. **To protect the rights and safety of** us and our employees, Members, owners, officers and others.
  4. **To meet legal requirements** such as complying with court orders and valid subpoenas.
  5. **To prosecute and defend** a court, arbitration or similar proceeding.
  6. **To support and improve the services we offer** including adding features and providing benchmarking and other comparison information based on aggregating and analyzing data.
  7. **To transfer your information** in the event of the sale of all, or substantially all, of the assets of our business to a third-party or in the event of a merger, consolidation or acquisition. However, in such event, any acquirer will be subject to our obligations under this Privacy Policy.
  8. **To provide information received hereunder to representatives and advisers** such as attorneys and accountants to help us comply with legal and other requirements.
  9. **To provide customer support and obtain feedback** about our Services, but only for and from the Member whose Personal Information and User Data are being used.

## Abandoned accounts

As a further measure against unauthorized access to account data and to more completely insure ReachMail's system integrity, any account which remains inactive for 7 months will be purged from the system. Periods of inactivity are measured from the last login date. Purges will include all account data including mailings, lists, users, and reports. Accounts that have been purged cannot be restored.

## Email Recipient Policy

Email is sent only to lists that have been warranted to us to be composed of opted-in subscribers of our clients. Any e-mail recipient may request at any time to be removed from those lists, and we will comply with that request within one business day. In addition, we will thoroughly investigate any allegations made by e-mail recipients relating to unsolicited e-mail.

## Subscriber Privacy

Data Collection: ReachMail allows customers to collect subscriber data only if that data is collected using legitimate opt-in methods-that is, the recipient actively entered their email into the customer's signup form, or the email came from an existing customer database.

**Use of purchased lists is prohibited.**

Confirmed Opt-In Process: When we host the subscription process for a client, this process is a confirmed opt-in. This means that after a person requests becoming a subscriber initially, they will receive a confirmation that they must respond to in order for a subscription to become valid.

## Anti-Spam Statement

Spam is jeopardizing the future of email marketing and we are adamantly opposed to the practice of sending spam. ReachMail practices permission-based e-marketing techniques and does not send spam or work with companies who do so.

## Abuse

Any individual or client who is suspected of abusing ReachMail services may be canceled at anytime. There will be no refunds to any monies paid for services. Abuse can be measured by subscriber feedback or by ReachMail's own internal auditing methods.

## Security Statement

Along with privacy, security is of utmost importance at ReachMail. Therefore, substantial investments have been made in ReachMail's technology platform including high-end servers and hosting, database applications, and security technologies.

To protect your information, our credit card processing vendor uses the latest 128-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology for secure transactions. In addition, our vendor is certified as compliant with card association security initiatives, such as the Visa Cardholder Information Security and Compliance (CISP), MasterCard®(SDP), and Discovery Information Security and Compliance (DISC).

ReachMail accounts require a username and password to log in. When you're finished using ReachMail, please click the "log out" link in the top right corner of your screen, to prevent someone from using your computer to access your account. You must keep your username and password secure and not disclose it to a third party.

Due to the sensitive nature of your Distribution Lists, we do not re-send forgotten passwords. Users must follow online instructions to reset their passwords if they forget them.

Account passwords are encrypted. We cannot see your passwords. We can only reset them.

## Notice of Breach of Security

Nobody is safe from hackers these days. ReachMail will notify you, as soon as possible, if a breach in security results in an unauthorized intrusion into our system which materially affects you or people on your Distribution Lists, and will subsequently report the corrective action taken in response to the intrusion.

* * *
